（ナレーション）＜西暦２１９９年＞
＜地球は
ガミラスとの戦いに敗れ→
滅びゆこうとしていた＞
＜人類滅亡まで　あと１年＞
＜宇宙戦艦ヤマトは　希望を求め→
１６万８０００光年のかなた
イスカンダルへ向け　旅立った＞
＜ヤマトは　途中
ガミラス冥王星前線基地を撃破＞
＜太陽系を離れ　ついに
外宇宙へと艦を進めていた＞
Episode 7: Farewell to the Solar System
ピッピー　ピッピー
（受信音）
（相原・通信）
藤堂本部長より　通信です。
Message from Project Chief Todo.
So you're already out there, at the edge of the Solar System?
（藤堂）太陽圏　外縁部か。
もう　そんな所に。
（沖田十三）
イスカンダルへの旅は遠大です。
The journey to Iscandar is lengthy.
We have only taken the first step.
我々は　まだ　その一歩を
踏み出したにすぎません。
True.
（藤堂）そうだな。　しかし→
But word that you've destroyed the Pluto base has reached Earth.
君たちから
冥王星基地　陥落の報が→
地球にもたらされた。→
There will be no more planet bombs.
遊星爆弾は　もう降ってこない。→
You have no idea how much relief that's brought.
それが　人々に　どれほどの安心を
もたらしたことか。→
ヤマトが
イスカンダルに向かっている→
Just knowing the Yamato is heading for Iscandar helps us keep going.
その事実だけでも
我々は　頑張れる。
ザザ…　ザザ…（ノイズ）
（藤堂・通信）だから　沖田君→
So, Okita, retrieve the Cosmo Reverse System.
必ず　コスモリバースシステムを
持ち帰って来てくれ。
Earth awaits the Yamato's return.
地球は　ヤマトの帰りを…。
ザザ　ザザー…
It awaits your return!
君たちの…　帰りだけを
待っているのだ…。
（相原）ヘリオポーズの影響が
出はじめているようです。
The heliopause is starting to interfere with our communications.
超空間通信の調整に→
Give me five minutes to prepare everything for hyperspace transmission.
５分ほど　時間を下さい。
うむ。
≪シューン（ドアの音）
It's rare to see you alone.
≫（伊東）一人とは　お珍しい。→
副長も　ご一緒かと。
I thought the XO would be with you.
You must have a lot of free time.
（新見）暇そうね。
（伊東）艦内で→
Unless there's trouble on board, security doesn't have much to do.
騒動でも起きないかぎり
保安部なんて　暇な仕事ですよ。→
そちらは　いかがです？
How are things going for you?
There isn't much for me to do until we reach a new star system.
（新見）新しい恒星系にでも
行かないかぎり→
暇な仕事ね。
ん？
（伊東）そういえば
乗員のカウンセリングも→
I've heard that you've begun counseling the crew.
始めたそうじゃないですか。→
Maybe you could spend some therapy time with me?
僕も診てもらおうかな～。
Stop joking around.
冗談はよして。
ピッ
（伊東）ヘリオポーズを越えると→
Once past the heliopause, we'll be unable to communicate with Earth anymore, right?
地球への交信は
できなくなるんでしょ？
The captain should let everyone send at least one final message there.
艦長も　最後の交信ぐらい
みんなに　させてやればいいのに。
あっ　そんなことをしたら
いらぬ里心が付いてしまいますね。
If he did, it could just make everyone more homesick.
Keep at it, then.
（伊東）
じゃあ　お仕事　頑張ってください。
（古代進）これ　新しい艦内シフト？
This is the updated shipboard duty list?
Hey...
（森雪）ねえ。
ん？
Back on Enceladus, didn't you ask me something strange?
エンケラドゥスで一緒のとき
私に　変なこと聞いてきたよね。
Are you related to any aliens?
（回想）
((君　宇宙人に　親戚とかいる？))
Did you mean Sasha?
あれって
もしかして　サーシャさん？
えっ？
最初は　なんのことか→
At first, I wasn't sure what you meant.
分からなかったけど
火星で　彼女を見てるんでしょ？
But you saw her on Mars, didn't you?
だから　そうかなって。
That's why I wondered.
Yeah, she looked a lot like you.
ああ。　似てたんだ　君に。
サーシャ・イスカンダル。
Sasha Iscandar...
命懸けで
波動エンジンの起動コアを→
The woman who gave her life to bring us the Wave Motion Engine's activation core.
届けてくれた人。
そういえばさ
彼女が来る１年前にも→
Come to think of it, wasn't there another who arrived a year earlier?
もう一人　来てたんだよね→
To bring the plans for the Wave Motion Engine itself?
波動エンジンの設計図を届けに。
ユリーシャ・イスカンダル。
Yurisha Iscandar.
えっ？
Her name.
彼女の名前よ。
（島）地球との最後の通信ですか？
あっ。
A last message to Earth?
うむ。　ヘリオポーズを越えると→
Yes. Once we've passed the heliopause,
powerful cosmic radiation will prevent communication with Earth.
ヤマトは
強力な銀河放射線の影響で→
地球との通信が　困難になる。
So I've decided to let anyone who chooses, speak with their family.
そこで
希望する者には　家族との交信を→
許可することにした。
（南部）ほんとですか？
Really?
Simultaneously,
（真田）それと同時に
太陽系赤道祭も行う予定だ。
we'll hold a line-crossing ceremony as we leave the Solar System.
Line-crossing is observed at the Equator, but this is space.
赤道って　ここ宇宙ですよ？
Once, sailors performed line-crossing ceremonies
かつて　大海原を行く船は
赤道を越える際→
航海の無事を祈って
赤道祭を行った。
when traversing the Equator, to ask for their ships' safety.
We shall do the same.
その故事に倣うのだ。
ははははっ！
ははっ。
≪（真琴）ええ～!?→
But Ota said you wear costumes to a traditional line-crossing ceremony.
だって　太田さんが　赤道祭は
伝統的に　仮装だって言うから…。
So he put you up to it, huh?
（島）担がれたね。
（篠原）はははっ！
マコっちゃんは　素直だね。
You believe anything you're told, Mako.
（真琴）んん～…　もう～！
太田さん　どこ行ったのよ!?
Where did you go, Ota?!
Honestly, you shouldn't listen to a word he says.
まあ　あいつの言うことを
真に受けるのが　そもそも…。
シャン！（鈴の音）
ん？
（篠原）あっ…。
（篠原・島）ええっ!?
（加藤）その…　俺は
似合ってると思うぞ。
Well, I think it looks good on you.
はい。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　キィーン…（ハウリング）
Thank you!
Everyone, because of your efforts, Operation M-2 was a success.
諸君。　諸君らの働きで→
メ２号作戦を
成功に導くことができた。
これでもう　地球に
遊星爆弾が落ちることはない。
No more planet bombs will strike Earth.
艦長として　礼を言う。
As your captain, I thank you.
We now begin the Solar System line-crossing ceremony.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　これより
太陽系赤道祭を始める。→
だが
航海は　まだ始まったばかりだ。→
But our voyage has only just begun.
Once this is over, do not look back toward Earth.
これが終わったら
地球を振り返るな。　前を見ろ。→
Look ahead.
イスカンダルまでの道を
見据えるのだ。
Keep your eye on the path that leads to Iscandar!
I pray for the line-crossing ceremony's success.
赤道祭の成功を祈る。
Cheers!
乾杯！
（一同）乾杯！
Cheers!
（佐渡）んん…　んん…。　ぷはぁ～！
ん？　どうじゃ？
お前も　一杯やらんか？
Want a drink, too?
I cannot drink.
（ＡＵ０９）私ハ　飲メマセン。
You're no fun...
つまらんやっちゃのう。
（艦内ＢＧＭ）
Supply Officer Hirata.
（玲）平田主計長。
（平田）あいつとは→
I was his classmate at the officer training academy.
士官学校で同期だったんだ。
Thank you for agreeing to my request.
（玲）わがままを聞いていただき
ありがとうございました。
If you dislike being a pilot, you're always welcome to come back.
（平田）嫌になったら
いつでも帰って来ていいよ。
（艦内ＢＧＭ）
（岩田）
甲板員は　貧乏くじだよなぁ。
The deck crew drew the short straw...
Ship repairs are our top priority.
（遠山）艦体の補修が優先だから→
So we don't get to talk to the folks back on Earth.
僕たちは
地球との交信は　お預けなんだな。
（岩田）あけみちゃ～ん！
Akemi!
（榎本・通信）私語が　だだ漏れだぞ。
No talking on duty.
（岩田）いっ!?　あっ　あぁ…。→
Yes, sir! It's just that I--
（通信）す…　すんません！
（遠山・通信）なんだな。
Enomoto!
（通信）榎本さん。
（榎本）ん？　古代か。
Kodai?
What's up? You need something?
どうした？　何か用か？
I mean, do you require something, sir?
じゃない…　用でありますか？
家族と通信したい人がいたら
自分が代わります。
If anyone wants to speak to their family, I'll switch with them.
But you...
だって　お前…。　あっ→
Oh, man.
参ったな…　そいつは命令ですか？
Is that an order?
Enomoto!
榎本さん！
（榎本）はははっ。
まあ　これで　１人は→
Well, that means one person will get to contact Earth.
地球と交信できるってわけだ。
No, two.
（玲・通信）いえ　２人です。
ん？
（佐伯）おい　あれ…。
（来島）ああ～　確か→
Isn't that...
Yes, the one who took out the Garmillas base with Lieutenant Kodai.
古代一尉と一緒に
ガミラス基地をたたいた…。
Hello, there.
（榎本）こいつぁどうも。　へへっ。→
Looks like the tactical officer has gotten better at dealing with women.
戦術長も　少しは
女の扱いが　上達したようですな。
What?
えっ　なんですか？
（榎本）佐伯！　来島！→
Saeki! Kishima!
お前ら　確か　新婚だろ？→
You guys just got married, right? Trade places with them.
代わっていただけ。
やった！
（佐伯・来島）
ありがとうございます！
Thank you sir!
ピッピッピッピッ…（キーボード操作音）
Captain, did you need something?
あっ　艦長。　何か　ご用ですか？
No, you look busy. Sorry to have bothered you.
いや…　忙しそうだな。
すまなかった。
はははっ！
やだ～！
Oh, no!
ふふふっ！
はははっ。
I don't know what's so fun...
（薮）何が楽しいんだか。
The Yamato will now be traversing the heliopause.
Jeez...
やだやだ…　あっ！
The ship may experience some turbulence.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）衝撃で　艦体が
揺れることも予想されます。→
All crew at the line-crossing ceremony, please take care.
赤道祭管下の乗組員は
注意してください。
（山崎）どうかしましたか？　艦長。
Something wrong, Captain?
Oh, no...
あっ　うん…　いや。
何か　ご用でも？
いや→
Do you need something?
No, it isn't that.
そういうわけじゃないんだが…。
いや　すまん　邪魔をしたな。
I'm sorry for bothering you.
≪シューン
ん？
This way to the comms room, to talk to Earth.
Now that it's finally happening, I don't know what to tell them.
≫いざとなったら
何を話していいのか…。
≫大丈夫。　元気な顔を見せれば…。
It's fine... Just show them you're okay.
Don't you have...
（徳川）君のところは　確か…。
おふくろと弟です。
A mother and younger brother. My dad...
おやじは…。
うん　知っとるよ。
I remember. He passed away during the first encounter with the Garmillans.
最初に　ガミラスと遭遇したとき
亡くなったんじゃな。
子供が生まれたんだ。
ちくしょう！→
My child's been born...
Man, we spent all our time just thinking of a name!
二人で名前を考えるだけで→
持ち時間が　終わっちまったよ。
うん　ふふふっ。
It's your turn, Engine Officer Tokugawa.
次は　徳川機関長ですよ。
（徳川）おっ？　わしか。
My turn?
（アイ子）わっ　じいじだ！
（徳川）おお～　アイ子。
It's Grandpa!
Oh, Aiko!
How are you? Tasuke, where are Hikoshichi and Kikuko?
元気か？
太助。　彦七と菊子さんは？
Um, well...
（太助・通信）あっ　その…。
ん？
They went to stand in line for food.
（太助）兄貴と義姉さんは
食料配給に並んでる。
太助～　アイ子　おなかすいたぁ。
Tasuke, I'm hungry!
もう少し　我慢しような。→
Just a little longer.
Recently, food hasn't been available as often.
ここんとこ　配給が滞ってて
実は　兄貴たち→
So they're getting it from the black market--
闇で　食料を…。
なんじゃと!?
What?
I told them to avoid the contraband so many times!
あれほど
闇物資には　手を出すなと…。
（通信）分かってるさ！
分かってるけど　そうしないと→
We know... We know, but we have no choice!
やっていけないんだよ！
んん…。
ねえ
じいじは　いつ帰って来るの？
When will you be back, Grandpa?
A year... A year, and then I'll bring back presents.
（徳川）１年だよ。　１年したら
お土産を持って　帰るからな。
Tasuke, look after Aiko. Earth's fate rests with you young people.
太助　アイ子を頼むぞ。
これからの地球は　お前たち
若い世代に懸かってるんじゃ。
うん…。
（徳川）なんじゃ？　男のくせに…。
Come on... Man up, and be strong.
Tasuke, Grandpa is crying, too!
太助　じいじも泣いてるよ。
Jiro?
（島）次郎！
（次郎）ん？　兄ちゃん！
Daisuke!
ははっ。
（島）母さんは？
Where's Mom?
Visiting Auntie at the hospital. She'll be back soon.
（次郎・通信）おばさんのお見舞い。
そろそろ帰って来るよ。
あっ…　そうか。
時間がないんだ。→
Oh, I see, but I don't have much time.
もしかすると　これが
最後の通信になるかもしれない。
This might be my last message to you.
えっ？　やだよ　そんなの！
（島）わがまま言うな。
Don't say that!
Don't be selfish.
Tell Mom that I'll see my mission through, just like Dad would've wanted.
母さんに伝えてくれ。
大介は　父さんの意志を継いで→
任務を全うします。
そして　必ず地球に戻ります。→
And I'll return to Earth, no matter what. Jiro, take care of Mom.
次郎　母さんを大切にしろ。
It's almost time.
（島）そろそろ時間だ。
ガチャ（ドアの音）
I'm back.
（沙織）ただいま。
あっ　お母さん　大介兄ちゃんだよ！
Mom, it's Daisuke!
（沙織・通信）えっ　大介が!?
母さん!?
Daisuke's here?
Mom... Wait! Just a little longer.
待ってくれ！　もう少し時間を…。→
Mom! Mom!
母さん　母さん！
（沙織）大介！
Daisuke!
あっ…。
Did you already talk to Earth?
君は　もう
地球との交信は終えたのか？
（玲）いえ。
いいのか？
- No.
- Sure you don't want to?
I'm sure.
（玲）いいんです　私は。→
I really am fine.
ほんとに大丈夫です。
あっ　君は
もしかして　ご両親が…。
Could your parents be...
Marsnoids? Yes, you can tell by my eye color.
マーズノイドだってことですか？
目の色で　分かっちゃいますよね。
祖父が　火星生まれでした。
My grandmother was born on Mars.
ちょうど　私が生まれた頃→
The Second Inner Planet War occurred right around when I was born.
第二次内惑星戦争があって→
そのあと　火星から地球に
強制移住させられて…。
After that, we were forced to move to Earth.
I see. So you have family on Earth?
そうか。　じゃあ　地球に　ご家族が。
いません。
みんな　遊星爆弾で…。→
No, they were all killed by the planet bombs.
たった一人残った兄も→
I had one brother left who died in battle with the Garmillans.
ガミラスとの戦闘で
亡くなりました。→
だから　気にしないでください。
So please don't worry about it.
Just like me.
僕と一緒だな。
えっ？
（南部）いきなりなんの冗談ですか。
（登紀子・通信）どう？→
What kind of joke is this?
Well? Her father owns Morita Pharmaceuticals.
「森田製薬」のご令嬢よ。
（南部）はぁ…。
Your father says he knows a high-ranking official with a nice daughter, but I think...
（登紀子）
お父様は　政府高官のご令嬢に→
いい人がいるって言うんだけど
私は…。
（南部）お母さん　今　僕らの
置かれた状況を考えてください。
Mother, consider our current situation.
You're the one who won't grasp the situation. You will take over the company.
（康造・通信）状況を
分かってないのは　お前の方だ！→
お前は　私の跡を継いで…。
僕は
お父さんの跡は継ぎません！→
I won't do it! And I'll choose my own wife.
そして　自分の伴侶は…。
（康造）お前は→
All you need to do is what I tell you!
私の言うことだけを
聞いていればいいんだ！
Kozo...!
（登紀子・通信）お父さん！
Yasuo, come home safely. Please...
康雄さん　必ず帰って来て。
必ずよ！
（南部）許してください。　僕には
心に決めた人がいるんです。
Please forgive me. I already have someone I've decided to marry.
Looks like Nanbu's done.
南部君　終わったみたいだな。
ん？
（百合亜）残り　あと２８人ほどです。
There are about twenty-eight people left.
Right, got it. By the way, I was glad to hear it.
（相原）うん　分かった。
そういえば　よかったね。
例の件　許可が下りて。
（百合亜）ありがとうございます。
That you got permission for that thing you mentioned.
Thank you!
Good luck. I'll put in a request when it's ready.
頑張ってね。　リクエストするよ。
Sure! Anyway, it was great that the captain let us all talk to Earth.
はい。　それにしても　みんなに→
地球との交信を許してくれた
艦長には　感謝ですよね。
Actually, the one who recommended it to him was...
それがさ
艦長に　これを勧めたのは…。
Me?
（新見）私？
（伊東）あれ？　違うんですか？→
Am I wrong? Didn't you suggest it to the captain?
艦長に　進言されたんでしょ？
（新見）
はぁ…　保安部は　詮索好きね。
Security likes to ask questions, doesn't it?
（伊東）あなたも
地球に　通信されておいた方が→
Shouldn't you be calling Earth, as well?
いいんじゃないですか？
（新見）分かってます。
I know.
That said, he's watching you...
（伊東）それはそうと…
彼　あなたを見てますよ。
（薮）あっ！　んん…。　えっ？→
うっ！
Once the Yamato leaves the heliopause, we can no longer contact Earth.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（百合亜）地球との交信は
ヘリオポーズを出ると→
できなくなります。
交信を希望する乗員で…。
Anyone wishing to, who has not completed the request form,
ちっ！　腰が据わってねぇな。
He needs to relax...
please do so at once.
ん？
飲めないの知ってるだろ。
You know I can't drink.
いいんですか？　隊長は。
Sure you don't want to go, Captain?
（加藤）
俺は　退路を断ってるからな。
There's no going back for me.
My dad will just tell me how I have to take over the temple.
どうせ　おやじは
寺を継げって話しかしないし。
Mine died in the first wave of planet bombing.
俺の父親　遊星爆弾の第１波で→
死んじまったんですよね。
大嫌いだったんですよ。
I hated him. He was always yelling.
いつも　どなってばかりで。
あっ…。
But now, I find I think of him a lot. Always the times he yelled at me.
それが　このごろ
不思議と　よく思い出すんです→
決まって
どなられたときのことをね。
やれやれ。
Jeez...
（玲）手が　かかりますね。
ああ。　大きな艦だからね。
This is a lot of work.
Type-99 Wave Motion Coil
Nanbu Heavy Industries
Yeah, it's a big ship.
Type-99 Wave Motion Coil
Nanbu Heavy Industries
ピピピピッ…
Type-99 Wave Motion Coil
Nanbu Heavy Industries
May I ask something?
一つ聞いていい？
（玲）えっ？
なんで　最初から
航空隊を　志願しなかったんだ？
Why didn't you volunteer for the pilot squad first?
あっ…　しましたよ。
I did. But the squad captain didn't want to let me.
でも　隊長は
私を入れたくなかったみたい。
You mean Kato? Why not?
加藤が？　どうして？
He may not look it, but he's more sensitive than most to matters of life and death.
（玲）ああ見えて　人の生き死にに→
人一倍　敏感な人なんです。
Come back alive!
生きて帰って来い！
はい！　あっ…。
Yes, sir!
（加藤）ありがとうございました…。
Thank you...
I think he didn't want me dying in combat like my brother.
（玲）たぶん　私を兄のように→
戦いで死なせたくなかったんです。
Those two were good friends. My brother and Captain Kato.
親友だったんです　あの二人…→
兄と加藤隊長。
（榎本・通信）ごほん！
（２人）あっ。
Sorry to interrupt, but could you go around, to assist the port side?
（榎本・通信）ああ～
邪魔して悪いが　お二人さん→
左舷の手伝いに
回っていただけませんでしょうか？
榎本さん。
ふふっ　了解。
All right, all right.
Roger!
（南部）あっ！
No!
（太田）嫌だ～！
（真琴）させるかぁ！
You won't get away.
（太田）ひぃ！
（真琴）んん～　へっへっへっ！→
太田！
酒つげって言ってるだろぉ？→
Ota... I told you to pour me a drink.
おい　おい！
（太田）勘弁してくれよ！
Please, no!
ふふふっ。
（真琴）飲みなさいよ！
You'd better drink too!
（真琴）うふふ～！
（太田）ひぃ～！
We will soon be completing our messages to Earth.
（南部）うわっ！
（太田）助けて～！
Help me!
Anyone wishing to speak to Earth, report to the communications room.
んん…　待てってのぉ～！
I said to wait...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（百合亜）
繰り返します。　地球との交信は→
間もなく　終了となります。
（南部）あれ？
That's...
You look well.
（土方・通信）元気そうだな。→
沖田は　どうだ？
佐渡先生には　頼んでおいたが。
How is Okita? I asked Doctor Sado to take care of him.
He's been much calmer lately.
最近は落ち着いているようです。
（土方）そうか。
I see.
I am very grateful to you for taking care of me over this past year.
この１年　育てていただいたこと→
感謝しています。
うん。→
Come back alive, all right?
必ず戻るんだぞ。
はい。
Yes.
≫コン　コン（ノック）
入れ。
Come in.
Is that you, Tokugawa?
徳川君か。
よろしいですかな？→
Do you have a moment?
It's already been a year, huh?
もう　１年ですか。
Yamazaki mentioned that you dropped by the engine room.
（徳川）山崎から聞きました。
機関部に　いらっしゃったとか。
Well, I...
いや　あれは…。
これに　ご用だったのでは？
Were you looking for this?
Tokugawa...
徳川君。
（徳川）ああ～。　最初の艦
覚えてらっしゃいますかな？
Do you remember our first ship?
ふふっ。　防衛艦三十六番→
Defense ship #36, a tiny ship they didn't even name.
艦名も付けてもらえない
小さな艦だった。
We were both so young.
お互い　若かったですな。
はははっ。
んん…。
あれから
何人の若者が　わしらより先に→
Since then, how many young ones have died while we've kept living?
逝ってしまったことか…。
数えたくないなぁ。
I don't even want to count... No, I cannot allow myself to count.
いや　数えてはならんのだ。
People's lives are more than mere numbers.
人の命は　数じゃない。
ええ。
Yes.
生き永らえた者にできるのは…→
All we survivors can do...
若者の明日に
希望をつなぐことだけだ。
...is ensure the young ones still have a hope for tomorrow.
That's all we can do to atone for taking so many of their lives.
多くの若者の未来を奪った
せめてもの償いですな。
（ハーモニカの演奏）
あっ。　補修作業　ご苦労さま。
Good job on the repair work.
えっ？
見えてたわよ。
I could see you.
I didn't have anything to do.
どうせ　やることなかったしな。
Why didn't you talk to Earth?
なんで　交信しなかったの？
My whole family's dead.
家族は　みんな死んだ。
あっ…。
What about you? Were you able to reach home?
君の方は　どうだったんだい？
家族とは話せたの？
そっちと同じかな。
I guess I'm the same as you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
あっ　ごめん…。
謝らないで。
Don't apologize.
私ね　昔の自分を覚えてないんだ。
えっ？
I can't recall my past...
All I can remember is this past year. I have no memories prior to that.
覚えてるのは
ここ１年間の記憶だけ。
その前の記憶はないの。
そうか。
I see.
The Yamato will now pass through the heliopause.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（百合亜）ヤマトは
間もなく　ヘリオポーズを通過。
（百合亜）それをもって
太陽系赤道祭は終了となります。→
At that time, the Solar System line-crossing ceremony will be complete.
Moving on...
それでは　変わりまして…。
は～い！　今日から始まります
「ＹＲＡラジオヤマト」。
Hello! We now bring you the first edition of YRA Radio Yamato!
Your host is everyone's favorite, Yuria Misaki! Let's begin our first song.
お相手は
皆さんの岬百合亜で～す。→
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　では早速　１曲目。→
赤道祭の最後にふさわしい
懐かしい曲を　お送りします。
An oldie but goodie, perfect for the end of the line-crossing ceremony.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　♪♪～（「真赤なスカーフ」）
Know that I'll return. A bright red scarf.
かならず帰るから
真赤なスカーフ
きっとその日も　迎えておくれ
On that day, come meet me once again.
今ははるばる
For now, I dream amongst the stars, at the end of the universe.
宇宙のはて
夢を見るのも　星の中
Come back soon!
旅する男の瞳は
When he travels, a man's eyes should always be full of romance.
ロマンをいつでも　うつしたい
ラララ…
Safe Travels
ラララ　真赤なスカーフ
A bright red scarf.
さようなら　地球。
Farewell, Earth.
We will return.
俺たちは　帰って来る。
必ず　帰って来るぞ～！
We are going to come back!
Then there's no problem, yes? You're Earth's last remaining hope.
（芹沢・通信）
では　問題はないのだな？→
もはや　地球の希望は
君たちだけだ。→
I'm counting on you, Lieutenant Niimi.
頼んだぞ　新見一尉。
ピピッ（通信が切れる音）
A trap waits in the skies.
Dark clouds gather, and up ahead, a red sun looms.
Its mouth is filled with burning fire, and its arms are Hell's crimson flames.
Fire one blast,
to break through an inescapable trap, and effect an impossible escape.
Next time: Wish Upon a Star.
There are 343 days left before humanity is extinct.
来日中の元従軍慰安婦の韓国人女
性が
沖縄の本土復帰の県民大会に出席
し、
日本政府に対して、軍の関与を認
め
謝罪するよう訴えた。